you say
당신은 말한다
Was it really Feng Qi who bandaged Jiang Zhaoguo?
Jiang Zhaoguo에게 붕대를 감은 것이 정말로 Feng Qi였습니까?
I do not know then
그때는 모르겠어
Does anyone know how Feng Qi was bandaged?
Feng Qi가 어떻게 붕대를 감았는지 아는 사람이 있나요?
Then he conspired with Jiang Zhaoguo
그러다가 장자오궈(江趙國)와 음모를 꾸몄다.
He was framed together
그 사람은 함께 모함을 받았어요
I would like to ask Mr. Jiang to do me a favor
장 씨에게 부탁 하나를 하고 싶습니다.
you say
당신은 말한다
I think he will definitely agree
내 생각엔 그 사람도 분명히 동의할 것 같아
That's it
그게 다야
Can Mr. Jiang
장 씨가 가능합니까?
When being interviewed by reporters
기자들과 인터뷰할 때
Use the figure-eight spiral method
8자 나선형 방법을 사용하세요
bandage his injured right arm
부상당한 오른팔에 붕대를 감다
This is the bandaging process
붕대를 감는 과정이에요
And when the photo was published in the newspaper
그리고 그 사진이 신문에 실렸을 때
Be sure to take a good look at his bandaged right arm
붕대를 감은 오른팔을 잘 보세요
What a strange request
정말 이상한 요청이네요
But for you
하지만 당신을 위해서
It doesn't seem surprising
별로 놀랄 일도 아닌 것 같은데
Wife
부인
You’ve read too much wild history
당신은 야생의 역사를 너무 많이 읽었습니다.
How could there be so much conspiracy?
어떻게 그렇게 많은 음모가 있을 수 있었습니까?
At most, God opens his eyes
기껏해야 신은 눈을 뜨고
Think Feng Qi has done many evil things
Feng Qi가 많은 악행을 저질렀다고 생각하세요
Plus my wisdom root, right?
게다가 내 지혜의 뿌리죠?
Was woken up all of a sudden
갑자기 잠에서 깨어났어
Discovered this detail about him
그에 대한 세부 사항을 발견했습니다
Anyway, in one sentence
아무튼 한 문장으로
It’s Feng Qi who deserves to be unlucky
운이 좋지 않은 사람은 Feng Qi입니다.
I think so too
나도 그렇게 생각해
Came back from get off work
퇴근하고 돌아왔다
You mean this big horse spoon?
이 큰 말 숟가락 말인가요?
This note I got
내가 받은 이 메모
It was really the information that Feng Qi passed on to Juntong.
실제로 Feng Qi가 Juntong에게 전달한 정보였습니다.
It's all Feng Qi's handwriting
모두 Feng Qi의 필체입니다.
It definitely can’t be fake
확실히 가짜일 리가 없어
Could it be that someone framed him?
누군가 그를 모함한 것이 아닐까?
he is so smart
그 사람 너무 똑똑해
Who could frame him?
누가 그를 모함할 수 있었습니까?
That Feng Qi who doubted you
당신을 의심했던 그 Feng Qi
I found someone to follow him
그를 따라갈 사람을 찾았어요
He went to Nanjing Pukou Station
난징푸커우역으로 갔어요
Looking for a vendor selling sachets
봉지 파는 상인을 찾습니다
Could it be that the sachet I lost is in Feng Qi’s hand?
혹시 내가 잃어버린 주머니가 풍기의 손에 있는 건 아닐까?
What's wrong? There's trouble.
뭐가 문제 야? 문제가 있습니다.
Who is following him?
그를 따르는 사람은 누구입니까?
My name is Li Youtian
내 이름은 리유텐이에요
Are you smart enough?
당신은 충분히 똑똑합니까?
no problem
괜찮아요
I want him to do something for me
그 사람이 나를 위해 뭔가 해주기를 바라요
Could it be this Li Youtian?
이 Li Youtian일까요?
Trick Feng Qi into writing something
Feng Qi를 속여 글을 쓰게 하세요.
Words with completely different meanings
전혀 다른 의미를 지닌 단어
Then select a few words and cut them out
그런 다음 몇 단어를 선택하고 잘라냅니다.
Where is Feng Qi framed?
Feng Qi의 액자는 어디에 있나요?
Let me say
내가 말하자
You write it
당신이 쓰세요
I guarantee that after Li Youtian arrives in Shanghai
Li Youtian이 상하이에 도착한 후 보장합니다
personal safety
개인의 안전
Promise to help Li Youtian
Li Youtian을 도와주겠다고 약속하세요
Bought Hong Xiang Ji’s three-yellow chicken
홍샹지의 노란 삼색 치킨을 샀어요
Fuyunzhai’s bean paste cake
푸윤자이의 된장 케이크
Reimburse all travel expenses
모든 여행 비용을 상환
And the cost of eating in restaurants
그리고 식당에서 식사하는 비용
I said you have read too many detective novels, right?
내가 탐정소설을 너무 많이 읽었다고 했지?
Who would put so much thought into it?
누가 그토록 많은 생각을 했을까요?
Frame him
그를 액자에 넣다
That makes sense
말이 되네요
Anyway, it’s Feng Qi
어쨌든 Feng Qi입니다.
Deserve bad luck
불운을 겪을 자격이 있다
right
오른쪽
Let's go
갑시다
I really don’t understand you very well
나는 정말로 당신을 잘 이해하지 못합니다
Say you're a traitor who's messing around
당신이 장난을 치는 배신자라고 해봐
Sometimes you are quite brave
가끔은 정말 용감한 당신
Not only brave but also thoughtful
용감할 뿐만 아니라 사려 깊음
I don't even know your beliefs
난 네 믿음도 모르겠어
what exactly is it
정확히 뭐야?
my faith
내 믿음
That is
그건
i love
좋아요
And what I love
그리고 내가 좋아하는 것
what do you love
당신은 무엇을 사랑합니까?
money
돈
And home
그리고 집
Let's go home
집에 가자
Lao Luo, look for me
라오루오야, 나를 찾아봐
Come, come, come
어떻게, 어떻게, 어떻게
What does it smell like to you?
당신에게 어떤 냄새가 나나요?
Zhao An is here
자오안이 여기 있어요
Yeah
응
He is now responsible for raising horses
그는 이제 말 사육을 담당하고 있습니다.
so
그래서
Horse shit taste
말똥맛
Such a great taste
정말 맛이 좋아요
Are you still in the mood to draw?
아직도 그림 그릴 기분이신가요?
Just because of the smell of horse manure
말똥 냄새 때문에
I'm inspired
나는 영감을 받았습니다
Look at the horse picture
말 그림을 보세요
abnormal
이상
What are you doing here?
여기서 뭐하는거야?
Handover
이양
His future trading group three
그의 미래 무역 그룹 3
The work is mine
일은 내꺼야
You're responsible for part of it
당신은 그것의 일부에 대한 책임이 있습니다
That won't work
작동하지 않습니다
What should I do with the general affairs department?
총무부서는 어떻게 해야 하나요?
Chief of the General Affairs Section, you are in charge.
총무과장, 당신이 책임을 맡고 있습니다.
He is just handing over the work to me temporarily.
그는 단지 일시적으로 나에게 일을 넘겨주는 것뿐이다.
But I hate the word "temporary" very much
하지만 나는 '임시'라는 단어를 매우 싫어한다.
do you understand
이해했나요
clear
분명한
And you
당신은요
I'll double your salary
연봉을 두 배로 해줄게
As for extra money, oil and water, etc.
여분의 돈, 기름, 물 등은
It depends on your own ability
본인의 능력에 따라 다릅니다
Where are Zhao An's people?
Zhao An의 사람들은 어디에 있습니까?
Basically, everyone is sitting on the bench.
기본적으로 모두가 벤치에 앉아 있습니다.
I'll leave everything that can be used to Damashio.
쓸 수 있는 것은 모두 다마시오에게 맡기겠습니다.
You finally got ahead
드디어 앞서나갔구나
Where is my younger brother?
내 남동생은 어디에 있나요?
I also had some soup to drink.
나는 또한 마실 수프를 먹었다.
Got a car for you
당신을 위한 차를 갖고 있어요
I'll drive your wife to work from now on
이제부터 당신 아내를 직장에 태워다 줄게요
No need, I have a motorcycle
필요 없어요. 오토바이가 있어요
hold
잡고 있다
Thank you bro
고마워 친구
By the way, let me ask you something.
그런데, 한 가지 물어보겠습니다.
Did Zuo Shuangtao come by train?
Zuo Shuangtao는 기차로 왔습니까?
what does it mean
무슨 뜻이에요
Lao Luo
라오루오
look at you
당신을 보면
Feng Qi kidnapped Kimura
펑치가 키무라를 납치했다
Such a big thing
이런 큰 일이라니
I have to write an inspection report
검사 보고서를 작성해야 해요
Talk about doubts
의심에 대해 이야기
Otherwise it can
그렇지 않으면 그럴 수 있다
can you understand me
나를 이해할 수 있니?
I asked her last night
내가 어젯밤에 그녀에게 물었어
She said that when she was working in Wuhan
그녀는 우한에서 일할 때 이렇게 말했습니다.
There is a man who likes her
그녀를 좋아하는 남자가 있어요
Do you know where she went to school in Nanjing?
그녀가 난징에서 어디 학교를 다녔는지 아시나요?
I bought her a Yunjin sachet
나는 그녀에게 윤진이 향낭을 사주었다
Although she doesn't like that man
그 사람은 그 사람을 좋아하지 않지만
But she likes this sachet very much
그런데 그 사람은 이 봉지를 아주 좋아해요.
Just left it
그냥 놔뒀어
That's it
그게 다야
Then when Zhao An asked her
그러다가 조안이 그녀에게 물었을 때
Why didn't she tell the truth?
그녀는 왜 진실을 말하지 않았습니까?
Isn't she afraid that I will know?
내가 알게 될까 봐 그녀는 두렵지 않은가?
Do I need to know that I can't rush her?
내가 그녀를 서두르면 안 된다는 걸 알아야 하나요?
So she said she bought it at the train station
그래서 그녀는 그것을 기차역에서 샀다고 하더군요
I didn't expect it would cause such a big deal.
나는 그것이 그렇게 큰 일을 일으킬 것이라고 예상하지 못했습니다.
Do you believe it
당신은 그것을 믿습니까?
I said
나는 말했다
Do you believe she doesn’t like that guy?
그 사람이 그 사람을 좋아하지 않는다고 생각하시나요?
I
나
Believe it
믿으세요
you hesitated
당신은 망설였다
Let me tell you in this day and age
요즘같은 시대에 말해줄게
Women can be very wild
여자는 매우 거칠 수 있습니다
You experience it firsthand
직접 경험해 보시고
Anyway, where is the woman?
그나저나 그 여자는 어디 있지?
I won't believe it
나는 그것을 믿지 않을 것이다
I trust my wife anyway
어쨌든 나는 내 아내를 믿는다.
These two swords of mine have been traveling around the world for decades.
내 이 두 개의 검은 수십 년 동안 전 세계를 여행해 왔습니다.
Do not kill unknown people with the sword
모르는 사람을 칼로 죽이지 마세요
I really didn't expect that
정말 그럴 줄은 예상 못했어요
I will actually use it to cut grass and feed horses one day.
언젠가 실제로 잔디를 깎고 말에게 먹이를 주는 데 사용할 예정입니다.
I'm Zhao An
저는 자오안이에요
How can I accept the humiliation here?
여기서의 굴욕을 어떻게 받아들일 수 있습니까?
God wants to kill me
신이 날 죽이고 싶어해
I must defy heaven
나는 천국을 거역해야 한다
You two have worked hard with me.
너희 둘은 나와 함께 열심히 일했다.
I'm going to die
나는 죽을 것이다
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
team leader
팀 리더
What's wrong
뭐가 문제 야
This horse has such a strong temper
이 말은 성격이 너무 강해요
Kicked me in the ass
내 엉덩이를 걷어차버렸어
Got kicked
쫓겨났어
you you
당신은
Why are you so stupid?
왜 그렇게 멍청해?
what can you do
당신은 무엇을 할 수 있나요
Let me do it
내가 하게 해줘
Be careful
조심하세요
Brother, what's wrong with you?
형님, 무슨 일이에요?
Brother you
형제 당신
Why are you so careless?
왜 그렇게 부주의합니까?
rolling
구르는
That's easy to say
그건 말이 쉽지
If you can, go and wipe the horse's body.
가능하다면 가서 말의 몸을 닦아주세요.
I'll go, I'll go
나는 갈 것이다, 나는 갈 것이다
Optimistic
낙관적인
wait
기다리다
put the knife down
칼을 내려놔
this horse
이 말
If a hair falls out
머리카락이 빠지면
I want it
나는 그것을 원한다
I want you to kill me
날 죽여줬으면 좋겠어
Optimistic
낙관적인
team leader
팀 리더
No need for him to yell
그 사람이 소리를 지를 필요는 없어
drink water drink water
물을 마셔라 물을 마셔라
Wait for him to come out
그 사람이 나올 때까지 기다리세요
Where was the kick?
킥은 어디에 있었나요?
you kick him
당신이 그를 걷어차
Don't hold it back
참지 마세요
good horse
좋은 말
What a good horse
정말 좋은 말이에요
Do you think he was fooled by the horse?
그가 말에게 속았다고 생각하시나요?
Kicked in the head, kicked in the temple
머리를 차고, 관자놀이를 차고
Xiaodouzi
샤오두지
This is the name I gave it
이건 내가 지은 이름이야
is that useful
그게 유용한가요?
Chief Kimura named it Takeda Shingen
기무라 대장은 다케다 신겐이라 명명
You call me Xiaodouzi
당신은 나를 Xiaodouzi라고 부르세요
soybeans
콩
elder brother
형
You call it Takeda Shingen
다케다 신겐이라고 하네
See if it answers or not
답변이 되는지 안 되는지 확인해보세요
Takeda Shingen
Takeda Shingen
Xiaodouzi
샤오두지
No trouble, no trouble
문제 없어, 문제 없어
Since the horse is so good to you
말이 너무 잘해주니까
starting today
오늘부터
You give the horse a bath
말을 목욕시키다
OK
좋아요
no problem
괜찮아요
trunk
트렁크
We have
우리는
new tasks
새로운 작업
team leader
팀 리더
What new tasks do we have?
우리에게는 어떤 새로운 임무가 있습니까?
Transport feed
운송 사료
interesting
흥미로운
ten little indians
열 꼬마 인디언
One person choked to death, and there were nine left.
한 사람이 질식해 숨졌고, 아홉 명이 남았습니다.
Nine little Indians sleep on one side
아홉 명의 인디언 꼬마가 한쪽에서 자고 있어요
One woke up and there were eight left
한 명이 일어났더니 여덟 명이 남았습니다.
Hello Mr. Zhu
안녕하세요, 주 씨.
Hello
안녕하세요
I don’t know Mr. Zhu
나는 주 씨를 모른다.
Is there any important information you want to tell me?
나에게 알려주고 싶은 중요한 정보가 있나요?
Is such that
그런가요?
I worked at J.P. Morgan Bank
JP모건은행에서 일했어요
Research money printing technology
돈 인쇄 기술 연구
A colleague of mine is a bronze sculptor
내 동료는 청동 조각가예요.
Later we returned to China together
나중에 우리는 함께 중국으로 돌아왔습니다
One day more than three months ago
3개월 전 어느 날
He gave me a call
그 사람이 나한테 전화를 했어
explain
설명하다
Suspecting that I am being followed
나를 미행하고 있다고 의심
We lost contact after that
그 이후로 연락이 끊겼어요
until recently
최근까지
One day he suddenly found me
어느 날 갑자기 그 사람이 나를 발견했어요.
Said he was kidnapped
납치됐다고 하네요
Imprisoned in an underground factory
지하공장에 갇히다
Forced to participate in counterfeiting legal tender
법정화폐 위조 참여 강요
Later he developed acute appendicitis
나중에 그는 급성 맹장염에 걸렸습니다.
Sent to hospital for treatment
치료를 위해 병원으로 이송됨
Only then did I find a chance to escape
그제서야 탈출할 기회를 찾았지
He asked me to help him leave Shanghai
그는 나에게 상하이를 떠나는 것을 도와달라고 부탁했다
and warned me that
그리고 나한테 이렇게 경고했어.
Those people are also asking about my whereabouts
그 사람들도 내 행방을 묻고 있어
Want me to be on guard
내가 경계하길 원해
I bought the ticket for him
나는 그 사람을 위해 표를 샀어요
come home
집에오다
But he disappeared
그런데 그 사람이 사라졌어요
The house is a mess
집이 엉망이야
obviously
확실히
The gang found him again
일행이 그를 다시 찾았다
and kidnapped him
그리고 그를 납치했다
Then I found out I was being followed
그러다가 내가 미행당하고 있다는 걸 알았어
He was almost kidnapped
그는 거의 납치될 뻔했다
I moved to the French Concession
프랑스 조계지로 이사했어요
Capture him
그를 잡아라
Do you know who he is?
그 사람이 누구인지 아시나요?
Special agent of the Military Section of the Japanese Army Ministry
일본 육군성 군사과 특수요원
Where is that underground factory?
그 지하공장은 어디에 있나요?
have no idea
전혀 모른다
He said he was kidnapped
납치됐다고 하더군요
and on the way to the hospital
그리고 병원 가는 길에
blindfolded
눈을 가린
That car also drove around on purpose.
그 차도 일부러 돌아다녔어요.
He cannot judge the distance of a place
그는 장소의 거리를 판단할 수 없다
I only know it's underground
지하에 있다는 것만 알아요
No sunshine all day long
하루종일 햇빛이 없어
Work, food and accommodation
일, 음식, 숙박
It's all there
다 거기 있어요
How many people are there in total in this factory?
이 공장에는 총 몇 명이 있습니까?
There must be dozens of people
수십 명은 있어야 해.
Some do printing
인쇄를 하시는 분들도 계세요
Making plates
접시 만들기
Making bronze sculptures
청동 조각품 만들기
Technical
인위적인
The equipment is also very complete
장비도 너무 완벽하네요
Most of these people were kidnapped.
이 사람들의 대부분은 납치되었습니다.
As long as you don't cooperate at work
직장에서 협조하지 않는 한
Or you are incompetent at work
아니면 직장에서 무능력한가?
will be executed
처형될 것이다
He witnessed three people being executed on the spot
그는 3명이 현장에서 처형되는 것을 목격했다.
In fact, my colleague
사실 내 동료는
He knows a little Japanese
그 사람은 일본어를 조금 알아요
Once he overheard their conversation
한번은 그가 그들의 대화를 우연히 들었을 때
Talk about this operation of printing counterfeit banknotes
위조 지폐 인쇄 작업에 대해 이야기해 주세요.
called cedar plan
삼나무 계획이라고 불리는
cedar plan
삼나무 계획
I heard that in addition to legal currency
법정화폐 외에
The Japanese are still trying to fake it
일본인들은 아직도 그것을 속이려고 노력하고 있다.
Border currency issued by the CCP’s border areas
중국 공산당 국경 지역에서 발행한 국경 화폐
Once counterfeit legal currency becomes widespread
위조 법정 화폐가 널리 퍼지게 되면
Not only the Chongqing government’s economic
충칭 정부의 경제뿐만 아니라
will be severely hit
심하게 타격을 받을 것이다
Even the people in the Kuomintang-controlled areas
국민당 통제 지역의 사람들조차도
Life will be even worse
인생은 더욱 나빠질 것이다
Strange
이상한
Why don't you say it doesn't kick two knives?
두 개의 칼을 차지 않는다고 말하지 않겠습니까?
We have a good relationship
우리는 좋은 관계를 갖고 있어요
Captain Zhao
자오 선장
Does it still hurt you?
아직도 마음이 아프나요?
I'll kick you, try it
걷어차줄게, 해봐
elder brother
형
Don't shoot bro
쏘지 마세요 형님
Turn around
돌아서 다
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
It's okay if you don't talk
말 안 해도 괜찮아
elder brother
형
Calm down bro
진정해요 형
stop
멈추다
what do you do
너 뭐하니
us
우리를
We are from a horse farm
우리는 말 농장 출신이다
Come and pull the feed
와서 피드를 당겨
Why did he call you Captain Zhao?
왜 그가 당신을 자오 선장이라고 불렀나요?
The racecourse is divided into several teams
경마장은 여러 팀으로 나누어져 있습니다.
I'm the captain of the feed team
나는 피드팀의 주장이다
Keep doing your work
계속 일을 하세요
Does anyone have any questions?
누구든지 질문이 있나요?
Don't tell me here
여기서는 말하지 마세요
yes
예
Don't worry, we're just here to do the work.
걱정하지 마세요. 우리는 단지 일을 하기 위해 여기에 있는 것뿐입니다.
brother
형제
Have you ever seen someone wearing a brown coat?
갈색 코트를 입은 사람을 본 적이 있나요?
People with injuries on their hands
손에 부상을 입은 사람들
No
아니요
we have been working
우리는 일해왔어
I didn't see anyone passing by
지나가는 사람 못봤는데
Thanks
감사해요
elder brother
형
you betrayed me
넌 나를 배신 했어
I don't
나는 아니에요
I just said I didn't see anyone
방금 아무도 못 봤다고 했어
Shoot
사격
put the gun down
총을 내려놔
lay down
누워
Been chasing me for more than half a month
반달 넘게 나를 쫓아다녔어
When crossing the Pinghan-Han Railway
평한한철도를 건널 때
I almost died in your hands
난 네 손에 죽을 뻔 했어
you traitor
너 배신자야
you guys
너희들
Just too merciful
너무 자비롭다
Nothing big can happen
큰 일은 일어날 수 없어
Shoot
사격
kill me
나를 죽여라
You can't escape either
너도 도망칠 수 없어
Who are they?
그들은 누구입니까?
Anti-Japanese elements
반일적 요소
Should we take them back?
다시 가져가야 할까요?
Injured brother
부상당한 형제
sorry
죄송합니다
elder brother
형
I almost got you in trouble
난 널 거의 곤란하게 만들 뻔했어
We're fine
우리는 괜찮아요
You're seriously injured
당신은 심각한 부상을 입었습니다.
Still bleeding
아직도 피가 난다
The bullet is still inside
총알이 아직 안에 있어요
I need to go to the hospital.
병원에 가야 해요.
I can't go to the hospital
병원에 갈 수가 없어요
Are you from Chongqing or Yan'an?
당신은 충칭(Chongqing)이나 옌안(Yan'an) 출신입니까?
I'm just a Chinese
나는 그냥 중국인이에요
I asked a little too much
제가 좀 많이 물어봤네요
We are also Chinese
우리도 중국인이다
trunk
트렁크
Isn't your cousin in a private clinic?
당신의 사촌은 개인 병원에 있지 않나요?
right
오른쪽
My cousin is very skilled in medicine
내 사촌은 의학에 아주 능숙해
Can help you take out the bullet
총알을 꺼내는 데 도움이 될 수 있습니다
right
오른쪽
Do not bother
귀찮게 하지 마세요
Get the stool quickly
빨리 변을 가져와
elder brother
형
Hurry up
서둘러요
sit
앉다
you saved our lives
당신은 우리의 생명을 구했습니다
We learned that a favor was repaid
우리는 은혜를 갚았다는 것을 배웠습니다
You are hurt so badly now
너 지금 너무 상처받았어
If you don't have surgery, your life will be gone.
수술을 하지 않으면 생명이 없어지게 됩니다.
real
진짜
Is it far
먼가요?
Far but not far
멀지만 멀지는 않은
But I don’t want to tell my cousin first.
하지만 사촌에게 먼저 말하고 싶지 않아요.
I think it works
내 생각엔 효과가 있는 것 같아
You go to your cousin first
먼저 사촌에게 가세요
Let him send the other patients away first
다른 환자들을 먼저 보내게 해주세요
What do you call me brother?
나를 뭐라고 부르나요?
Call me Lao Tian
라오티안이라고 불러주세요
Brother Tian
티안 형제
You call me Xiao Zhao
당신은 나를 샤오자오라고 부르죠
His name is Trunk
그 사람 이름은 트렁크예요
You have difficulty moving now
지금은 움직이는 데 어려움이 있습니다.
Take my carriage
내 마차를 가져가세요
I pull you over slowly
천천히 널 끌어당겨
trunk
트렁크
You go now
당신은 지금 이동
Go to your brother's place
형님 집으로 가세요
Arrangements have been made to come and greet us.
와서 우리를 맞이할 준비가 되어 있었습니다.
OK
좋아요
Brother Tian
티안 형제
Believe me
나를 믿어
But
하지만
Is there anyone who loves him more than me?
나보다 그 사람을 더 사랑하는 사람이 있을까?
how long have you been together
얼마나 오랫동안 함께 있었어?
do you love him very much
당신은 그를 매우 사랑합니까?
Miss Hanlu
미스 한루
you
너
But haven't you already
하지만 이미 그러지 않았나요?
terribly sorry
정말 죄송 해요
Shouldn't appear like this
이렇게 나타나서는 안 된다
No
아니요
I'm the one who should be sorry
미안해해야 할 사람은 나야
I'm glad that Mr. Yamashita is still alive.
야마시타 씨가 아직 살아있어서 다행이에요.
But I just behaved
하지만 난 그냥 행동했어
But so rude
그런데 너무 무례하다
do you know
당신은 알고 있나요
when people are dying
사람들이 죽어갈 때
Will see myself without the body
몸이 없는 내 모습을 보게 될 거야
that moment
그 순간
I really saw myself
정말 내 모습을 봤어
if i can survive
내가 살아남을 수 있다면
I must start over
다시 시작해야 해요
My life
내 인생
You must have been seriously injured at the time
그 때 크게 다쳤나 봐요.
Two-thirds of my lung was removed
폐의 3분의 2가 제거됐어요
I can no longer be a soldier
나는 더 이상 군인이 될 수 없다
So Mr. Yamashita is now
그래서 야마시타 씨는 지금
I am an ordinary businessman now
나는 이제 평범한 사업가이다
i love movies
나는 영화를 좋아해요
This beautiful flower moon
이 아름다운 꽃달
This is the first movie I invested in
제가 투자한 첫 번째 영화입니다.
Ms. Hanlu joins the team
한루 씨가 팀에 합류했습니다
I believe
나는 믿는다
will be a great success
큰 성공을 거둘 것이다
It turns out that you invested in this movie
이 영화에 투자한 것으로 밝혀졌습니다
No wonder it looks like willow
당연하게도 버드나무처럼 생겼어요
Big stars like Chen Juanjuan
Chen Juanjuan과 같은 빅 스타
Everyone is willing to play some small roles
모두가 작은 역할을 기꺼이 수행합니다.
Compared with Miss Hanlu
미스 한루와 비교하면
They are only suitable for small roles
작은 역할에만 적합합니다.
where
어디
My career has stalled for the most part
내 경력은 대부분 중단됐어
The audience almost forgot about me
청중은 나를 거의 잊어버렸다
but
하지만
i will never forget you
나는 결고 널 잊을 수 없어
but I
하지만 나는
Mr. Yamashita
Mr. Yamashita
I think you should also know
너도 알아야 할 것 같아
I already feel like I belong
나는 이미 소속감을 느낀다
you mean
네 말 뜻은
Mr. Jiang
장 씨
Although I do
내가 그러긴 하지만
It’s not what a gentleman does
그건 신사가 할 일이 아니야
But I really can't bear it
그런데 정말 견딜 수가 없어
See Miss Hanlu again
한루씨를 다시 만나보세요
be deceived again
또 속다
My sincerity has been let down again
내 진심이 또 무너졌어
I believe in tomorrow's drama
내일 드라마를 믿어요
will be more exciting
더 흥미로울 것이다
That
저것
I'll take my leave first
나 먼저 이만 떠날게
How's the injury?
부상은 어때요?
Fortunately, no artery was injured.
다행히 동맥은 다치지 않았습니다.
Arrange surgery as soon as possible
최대한 빨리 수술을 준비하세요
good
좋은
Brother Tian
티안 형제
Here is Dr. Han
여기 한 박사님이 계십니다.
rest assured
안심하세요
Have you explained everything?
다 설명하셨나요?
Don't worry, I've explained it.
걱정하지 마십시오. 내가 설명했습니다.
Doctor Han is our informant
한 박사님은 우리의 정보원입니다
absolutely reliable
절대적으로 신뢰할 수 있는
team leader
팀 리더
Who is this Lao Tian?
이 Lao Tian은 누구입니까?
of the Chinese Communist Party
중국 공산당의
How did you know
어떻게 알았어?
Do you remember the man in the coffee coat?
커피 코트를 입은 남자를 기억하시나요?
Say to Lao Tian
라오티엔에게 말해보세요
When passing the Pinghan Railway
평한철도를 지나갈 때
I almost died at the hands of Lao Tian
나는 라오티안의 손에 죽을 뻔했다
Maybe they came from Yan'an
어쩌면 옌안에서 왔을 수도 있어요
The Pinghan-Hankou Railway is the only way to go
핑한-한커우 철도가 갈 수 있는 유일한 길입니다
Makes sense
말이된다
Nao Tian said that the coffee jacket is a traitor
Nao Tian은 커피 재킷이 배신자라고 말했습니다
what's going on
무슨 일이야
I guess it’s an internal campaign by the Chinese Communist Party.
아마도 중국 공산당의 내부 캠페인인 것 같습니다.
Chased all the way here
여기까지 쫓아왔어
Then why don't we
그럼 우리는 어때?
Just take him back for interrogation.
심문을 위해 그를 다시 데려가세요.
Can you please give me some ideas?
나에게 몇 가지 아이디어를 주실 수 있나요?
The CCP has extremely hidden communication lines in Shanghai
중국 공산당은 상하이에 극도로 숨겨진 통신 회선을 가지고 있습니다
Lao Tian is injured now
Lao Tian은 현재 부상을 입었습니다.
He let the traitor escape again
그는 배신자를 다시 탈출시켰습니다
He will definitely contact their people
그는 확실히 사람들에게 연락할 것이다
We must not alert the enemy
적에게 경고해서는 안 된다
Zhangji trap setting
장지 트랩 설정
Only then can we defeat the Hulao Dragon
그래야만 호라룡을 물리칠 수 있다
Understood
이해했다
Walk
걷다
team leader
팀 리더
Slow down
천천히 해
This person's name is Magpie
이 사람 이름은 까치야
He's a lurker we planted in Yan'an
그 사람은 우리가 옌안에 심은 잠복꾼이에요
Recently arrived in Shanghai
최근 상하이에 도착했습니다.
But his whereabouts are unknown
하지만 그의 행방은 알 수 없다
Gotta find him
그를 찾아야 해
Why are we in Yan'an?
우리는 왜 옌안에 있는 걸까요?
Place latent personnel
잠재 인원 배치
Don't ask so many questions
질문을 너무 많이 하지 마세요
Don't ask anything
아무것도 묻지 마세요
There must be many ulterior conspiracies.
은밀한 음모가 많을 것입니다.
What did you say
뭐라고 하셨나요
nothing
아무것도 아님
Also
또한
Just a clue
단지 단서
He has a lover in Shanghai
상하이에 애인이 있어요
Called Cai Hongling
카이홍링(Cai Hongling)이라고 불림
She's a dancer at Xian Lesi Ballroom
그녀는 Xian Lesi Ballroom의 댄서입니다.
You have to find a way to get to her
그녀에게 다가갈 방법을 찾아야 해
What is the purpose of looking for magpies?
까치를 찾는 목적은 무엇입니까?
He has something important in his hand
그 사람 손에 중요한 뭔가가 들려있어
what
무엇
Hello
안녕하세요
Mr. Chen
첸 씨
Miss Hanlu
미스 한루
hello
안녕하세요
I called just to ask.
그냥 물어보려고 전화했어요.
Is Mr. Chen free tomorrow morning?
첸 씨는 내일 아침에 시간 있어요?
should have
가지고 있어야 한다
What's up
무슨 일이야
some things
몇 가지
I would like to ask Mr. Chen for a favor
첸 선생님께 부탁 하나 드리고 싶습니다.
Is it about the fan association again?
또 팬협회 얘기야?
Roughly the same
대략 동일
OK
좋아요
So where shall we meet?
그럼 우리 어디서 만날까?
You can come directly to my house
우리 집으로 직접 오셔도 돼요
Go to Miss Hanlu’s house
한루씨 집으로 가세요
You won't be photographed by tabloid reporters, right?
타블로이드 기자들이 사진을 찍지는 않겠죠?
Then I can't explain it to my wife.
그러면 아내에게 설명할 수가 없어요.
can you come
너 올 수 있니?
I feel relieved
마음이 편해진다
some things
몇 가지
I don't want someone I hate to do it.
내가 싫어하는 사람이 그런 짓을 하는 건 싫다.
Miss Hanlu's voice
한루씨의 목소리
It sounds a little hoarse
좀 쉰 목소리로 들리는데
Maybe I've been too tired recently
어쩌면 내가 최근에 너무 피곤했는지도 몰라
That's settled
그건 해결됐어
tomorrow morning
내일 아침
I will definitely be at home
난 분명 집에 있을 거야
good
좋은
See you or leave
만나거나 떠나거나
some things
몇 가지
I don't want someone I hate to do it.
내가 싫어하는 사람이 그런 짓을 하는 건 싫다.
tomorrow morning
내일 아침
I will definitely be at home
난 분명 집에 있을 거야
why did she say that
그 사람이 왜 그런 말을 했어?
Miss Hanlu
미스 한루
I’m off duty
난 비번이야
Don’t you know I’m number 76?
제가 76번인 걸 모르시나요?
Tell me to get off work
퇴근하라고 말해
correct
옳은
recently
최근에
Do you have any suspicious people here?
여기 수상한 사람이라도 있나요?
No
아니요
valuable information now
지금의 소중한 정보
The reward is double
보상은 2배
You, the informants, are the most profitable now.
제보자인 당신들이 지금 가장 수익성이 좋은 사람입니다.
I don’t even want to do it anymore
더 이상 하고 싶지도 않아
You can be an informant
제보자가 될 수 있습니다
Captain Zhao?
자오 선장?
That old Tian seems to be suspicious.
그 늙은 Tian은 의심스러운 것 같습니다.
what happened
무슨 일이에요
Where is he now?
그는 지금 어디에 있나요?
Still upstairs
아직 위층에 있어요
You stabilize him first
당신이 먼저 그를 안정시키세요
I'll be here in a minute
나 곧 여기에 올게
good
좋은
wait
기다리다
Notify the gendarmerie
헌병대에 알린다
Why
왜
Leave it alone
내버려둬
I asked you to notify the gendarmerie
헌병대에 알려달라고 했어요
yes
예
Laotian
라오스어
Who is it?
누구입니까?
play high
높이 놀다
Is something wrong at this late hour?
이 늦은 시간에 무슨 일이라도 있는 걸까요?
I'm here to say goodbye to you
나는 당신에게 작별 인사를 하러 왔습니다
Say goodbye
작별 인사
Come in and talk
들어와서 얘기해
Been here before
전에 여기에 왔었어
First time here
여기에 처음으로
you want to ask me
나한테 물어보고 싶은 거야?
How do you know you live here?
당신이 여기 살고 있다는 것을 어떻게 알 수 있나요?
I didn’t know until you came, too.
나도 당신이 오기 전까지는 몰랐어요.
Where is Chen Jiaping?
천자핑은 어디에 있나요?
Not at home?
집에 없다?
Working overtime
초과 근무
Coming back soon
곧 돌아옵니다
you sit
당신은 앉아
We don’t have any coffee powder at home
우리 집에는 커피가루가 하나도 없어
Let me get you a cup of tea
차 한잔 드릴까요
no, I'm fine
아냐 난 괜찮아
I'll leave after saying a few words to you
몇 마디만 하고 떠날게
I'm leaving Taihe Trading Company
저는 태화무역회사를 떠납니다
Why
왜
in Shanghai
상하이에서
There's a reclusive British communications expert
은둔한 영국 통신 전문가가 있어요
Eisen Meyer
아이젠 마이어
I visited him some time ago
나는 얼마 전에 그를 방문했다.
He quite appreciates me
그 사람은 나를 정말 고맙게 생각해요
And he promised
그리고 그는 약속했다
If I stop doing things for the Japanese
내가 일본인을 위한 일을 그만두면
He accepted me as his disciple
그분은 나를 제자로 받아들이셨습니다
The salary level and everything are pretty good.
급여수준이나 모든게 괜찮은 편입니다.
I'm quite interested
꽤 관심이 있어
But our business
하지만 우리 사업은
You can't leave if you want to, right?
떠나고 싶으면 떠날 수 없잖아요?
I submitted my application
신청서를 제출했습니다
I want to go back and take care of my seriously ill grandma
돌아가서 중병을 앓고 있는 할머니를 간호하고 싶다
And I deliberately in my recent work
그리고 나는 최근 작업에서 일부러
Showing no results
결과가 표시되지 않음
Make mistakes frequently
실수를 자주 하세요
They probably think I'm a loser
아마 내가 패배자라고 생각할 거야
Of no use
소용없다
For this reason
이러한 이유로
Can they let you go easily?
그들이 당신을 쉽게 보내줄 수 있나요?
The nature of my job
내 직업의 성격
It stands to reason that it's not that easy
그렇게 쉬운 일이 아닌 것은 당연한 일이다
but you know
하지만 너도 알지
People want to leave
사람들은 떠나고 싶어해
Who can keep it?
누가 그것을 지킬 수 있나요?
And I checked it up and down
그리고 위아래로 확인해 봤는데
There was some blood
피가 좀 났어요
These days
요즘에는
Nothing can be done without spending money
돈을 쓰지 않고는 아무것도 할 수 없다
Actually
실제로
I already thought that place was not suitable for you
나는 이미 그 곳이 당신에게 적합하지 않다고 생각했습니다
fine
괜찮은
Learn techniques from British experts
영국 전문가로부터 기술을 배워보세요
happy for you
당신을 위해 행복
I also look forward to seeing a better you
나도 기대해 더 좋은 모습으로 만나길 바라
Thanks
감사해요
otherwise
그렇지 않으면
Let me be your brother
내가 당신의 형제가 되게 해주세요
Okay
좋아요
Such an excellent brother
정말 훌륭한 동생이에요
Who does not like
누가 좋아하지 않니?
OK
좋아요
Then we've settled
그럼 우리는 합의했어요
Sister, I'm leaving
언니, 나 갈게요
How can I contact you in the future?
앞으로 어떻게 연락할 수 있나요?
rest assured
안심하세요
I won't go too far
너무 멀리 가지 않을 거야
I still want to protect you
그래도 난 널 지키고 싶어
By the way, sister
그런데 언니
That's it
그게 다야
Search
찾다
gendarmerie
헌병대
He just called the gendarmerie
방금 헌병대에 전화했어요
you killed their people
당신은 그들의 사람들을 죽였습니다
They won't let you go
그들은 당신을 놓아주지 않을 거예요
You go quickly
빨리 가세요
leave me alone
나를 내버려둬
Brother Tian
티안 형제
I brought you here
내가 널 여기로 데려왔어
Almost killed you
거의 당신을 죽일 뻔 했어요
If I leave by myself
나 혼자 떠나면
Am I still Chinese?
나는 아직도 중국인인가?
Walk
걷다
Search
찾다
Leave the scene to other departments for investigation
조사를 위해 현장을 다른 부서에 맡기다
Walk
걷다
Brother Tian
티안 형제
Come and stay at my house tonight
오늘 밤 우리 집에 와서 묵어라
No more
더 이상은 없어
I can't trouble you anymore
더 이상 당신을 힘들게 할 수 없어요
I know something like this happened
나도 이런 일이 있었던 줄 알아
You won't believe me
당신은 나를 믿지 않을 것입니다
I'm just worried
걱정이 될 뿐이야
You are very weak now
당신은 지금 매우 약해요
You are familiar with this place
당신은 이 장소를 잘 알고 있습니다.
Can you help me find a hotel first?
먼저 호텔을 찾는 것을 도와주실 수 있나요?
Let's talk about staying here
여기에 머무르는 것에 대해 이야기하자
no problem
괜찮아요
Jiaping
자핑
you're awake
당신은 깨어 있어요
You stayed with me all night
넌 밤새도록 나와 함께 있었어
I'm thinking
나는 생각 중입니다
if you wake up
네가 깨어나면
Found no one there
거기엔 아무도 없었어
in this empty room
이 텅 빈 방에
Then I really don’t know
그럼 난 정말 모르겠어
Is it heaven or earth?
하늘인가, 땅인가?
I wish this was heaven
여기가 천국이었으면 좋겠다
But I don’t want you here
하지만 난 당신이 여기 있는 걸 원하지 않아요
Then don't you think
그렇다면 당신은 생각하지 않습니까?
no matter it's me
상관없어 그게 나야
still you
아직도 당신
Shouldn't they all be here?
다들 여기 있어야 하지 않나?
You must think I'm stupid, right?
넌 내가 바보라고 생각하겠지?
Actually
실제로
There are many ups and downs in life
인생에는 우여곡절이 많다
Some hurdles are really difficult to pass
일부 장애물은 통과하기가 정말 어렵습니다.
But in this way you
하지만 이런 식으로 당신은
I went through this hurdle personally.
저는 개인적으로 이 난관을 겪었습니다.
Although it's a bit more tragic
좀 더 비극적이기는 하지만
But it's worth it
그러나 그것은 그만한 가치가있다
Why don't you go back quickly?
빨리 돌아가는 게 어때?
If the man I love leaves me
내가 사랑하는 남자가 나를 떠난다면
But he stayed out all night with another woman
그런데 그 사람은 다른 여자랑 밤새도록 놀았어
I have to kill him
나는 그를 죽여야 해
Then do you think she won't do this?
그러면 그 사람이 이런 짓을 안 할 것 같나요?
Even though you say so
그렇게 말하는데도
But actually I know you love each other very much
하지만 사실 나는 당신이 서로를 매우 사랑한다는 것을 알고 있습니다
I really envy you
정말 부럽다
It's so quiet now
지금은 너무 조용해요
Just like the silence before the war broke out
전쟁이 일어나기 전의 침묵처럼
Next
다음
I have to face the swarm of reporters
수많은 기자들과 마주해야 해
Take me as the director who asked
저를 요청한 감독으로 받아주세요
Producer
생산자
movie studio owner
영화 스튜디오 주인
When I think of these
이것들을 생각하면
Might as well continue to stay here
여기 계속 머무르는 게 나을지도 몰라
That
저것
Just think about one more thing
하나만 더 생각해 보세요
I still have to face my lovely wife
난 아직 내 사랑스러운 아내를 만나야 해
I have a feeling you'll be fine
당신이 괜찮을 것 같은 느낌이 들어요
Go back quickly
빨리 돌아가라
I won't do stupid things again
다시는 어리석은 짓은 하지 않을게
Captain Zhao
자오 선장
as you would expect
당신이 예상했던대로
Lao Tian changed to a hotel early in the morning
Lao Tian은 아침 일찍 호텔로 변경했습니다.
Are you tracking?
추적하고 있나요?
Followed
팔로우됨
He moved to the Chang Lai Hotel three streets away.
그는 세 거리 떨어진 창라이 호텔로 이사했습니다.
team leader
팀 리더
You said you went through so much effort to save him yesterday
어제 그를 구하기 위해 너무 많은 노력을 했다고 하더군요
Why does he still not trust you?
그 사람은 왜 아직도 당신을 믿지 않는 걸까요?
I didn't save him just to make him believe in me.
나는 단지 그 사람이 나를 믿게 만들려고 그를 구한 것이 아닙니다.
Even if he believes me
그 사람이 나를 믿어도
He won't let me know his whereabouts
그 사람은 나에게 자신의 행방을 알려주지 않을 거야
I know the people of the CCP very well
나는 중국 공산당 사람들을 아주 잘 압니다.
Very cunning
매우 교활하다
Then why are we saving him?
그럼 우리는 왜 그를 구하는 걸까요?
Follow the clues
단서를 따라가세요
Doctor Han is dead now
한 박사님은 이제 돌아가셨어요
The clues to find him are gone
그를 찾을 수 있는 단서는 사라졌다
Then he will think that the danger has been removed
그러면 그는 위험이 제거되었다고 생각할 것입니다
Will wait for the opportunity
기회를 기다릴 것이다
Then I'll arrange someone
그럼 내가 사람을 정리할게
Follow him every step of the way
모든 단계에서 그를 따라가세요
remember
기억하다
follow him
그를 따라가다
Have to change someone every half hour
30분마다 사람을 바꿔야 해요
cannot be repeated
반복될 수 없다
clear
분명한
After my two days of observation and research,
이틀간의 관찰과 연구 끝에,
I discovered that adzuki beans cannot eat leguminous grasses
팥이 콩과 식물을 먹을 수 없다는 사실을 발견했습니다
Look at this shit
이 똥 좀 봐
Severe indigestion
심한 소화불량
I know Xiaodouzi
나는 Xiaodouzi를 안다
Just feel sick to your stomach
그냥 배가 아프다
Feeling depressed
우울한 느낌
When you feel depressed, life will not be happy.
우울함을 느끼면 인생은 행복하지 않을 것입니다.
It seems that it is better to eat alfalfa in the future.
앞으로는 알팔파를 먹는 것이 좋을 것 같습니다.
I said you really use yourself as a stable driver.
정말 안정적인 운전자로 활용하신다고 하더군요.
This is what I call doing what I do and loving what I do.
이것이 바로 내가 하는 일을 하는 것과 내가 하는 일을 사랑하는 것입니다.
You know shit
그거 알아?
team leader
팀 리더
how's it going
어떻게되고 있습니까
There is progress
진전이 있다
Lao Tian went to the newspaper office
Lao Tian은 신문사에 갔다
Why go to the newspaper office?
왜 신문사에 가나요?
A missing person notice was posted
실종자 안내문이 게시되었습니다.
Dong Lizhen female
동리진 여성
Thirty-seven years old
서른일곱 살
This is their code for contacting each other.
이것은 서로 연락하기 위한 코드입니다.
right
오른쪽
But we can't understand
하지만 우리는 이해할 수 없어요
It doesn’t matter if you don’t understand
이해하지 못해도 상관없어
Explain Lao Tian
라오티엔(Lao Tian)에 대해 설명해보세요
Started contacting their people
사람들에게 연락하기 시작했습니다
good thing
좋은 것
Prepare two clothes
옷 두 벌을 준비하세요
I will follow up personally tomorrow
내일 개인적으로 후속 조치를 취하겠습니다.
yes
예
elder brother
형
I just heard what you said about Tian Bu Tian.
방금 당신이 Tian Bu Tian에 관해 말씀하신 것을 들었습니다.
If you can let little beans spread happily in the fields,
작은 콩을 들판에 즐겁게 퍼뜨릴 수 있다면
run two steps
두 단계를 실행
I believe it will be of great benefit.
큰 유익이 되리라 믿습니다.
roll
롤
gentlemen
신사
Is there fire?
불이 났나요?
What do you smoke?
당신은 무엇을 담배를 피우나요?
laodaopai
라오다오파이
Made in UK
영국에서 제작됨
Your lighter is
당신의 라이터는
Langson diesel lighter
랭슨 디젤 라이터
American man-made
미국산 인공
Hello comrade
안녕 동지
Hello
안녕하세요